Barry Faulkner
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
- Writings, 1912-1966, Series 3:; (Boxes 1-2; 1.0 linear foot)
  - Writings by Others (Box 2)
    - After the Artists Were Gone by H.S. Bennion, 1912 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - [Interview With Barry Faulkner Regarding Augustus Saint-Gaudens] by John Bond, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Mural Paintings in the Forum of the Education Building For the Commonwealth of Pennsylvania at Harrisburg by Eric Gugler, circa 1950s-1960s (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Villa Bosco Parasio by Eric Gugler, 1920 (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - Herbs and Gardens by Frederika James, 1960, (not scanned) (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - Margaret Fitch Brewster by Frederika James, 1964, (not scanned) (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - Barry Faulkner, 1881-1966 by Leon Kroll, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - Bosco Parrasio, Rome by Edward Lawson, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - [On Faulkner] by Paul Manship, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - Olivia Rodham by Robbins Milbank, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - History and Ideal of American Art [excerpt] by Eugene Neuhaus, 1931 (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - [Quotation of Christopher Marlowe], circa 1910s-1920s (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - Pluperfect Progressive by Sidney Waugh, circa 1910s-1940s (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - [Poems] by Lawrence White, circa 1920s-1950s, (not scanned) (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - Murals of Old Keene by [unknown], circa 1938 (Box 2, Folder 50)
- Sketchbooks and Sketches, circa 1910s-1930s, Series 4:; (Boxes 2-3; 8 folders)
  Four sketchbooks by Faulkner contain pencil and ink drawings of landscapes, city scenes, architecture, figures, faces, animals, trees, and water. Also included are drawn copies of artwork by others including murals, sculptures, mosaics, Asian art, Egyptian art, Greek art, and objects such as furniture and clothing. The first sketchbook contains notes on the relationship between the body, color, and the zodiac; notes on astrology; and detailed notes about where sketches were copied. Also found in this series are a small pencil sketch of a foot and a large pastel sketch of a landscape.
  Artwork by others includes two sketches by Margaret Platt including one of Faulkner's studio from 1922, and three drawings which are similar stylistically but whose creator is unknown.
  - Four Sketchbooks, circa 1900s-1920s, (4 folders) (Box 2, Folder 51-54)
  - Sketches, circa 1920s-1930s, (Oversized housed in Box 3) (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Artwork by Others (Box 2)
    - Margaret Platt, circa 1920s-1930s (Box 2, Folder 56)
    - Unknown Artist(s), circa 1920s-1930s (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - Oversized Sketches, circa 1900s-1940s, (Scanned with Box 2, Folder 53) (Box 3 (sol), Folder 2)
- Diaries, 1922-1956, Series 5:; (Boxes 2; 6 folders)
  Five travel diaries from 1922 to 1924 document Faulkner's trips to Europe, Africa, and Asia including stops in France, Italy, Egypt, and Turkey. Entries describe Faulkner's impressions of places, architecture, artwork, tourist sites, restaurants, and accomodations. Topics include French churches, the artwork of Andrea Mantegna and Piero della Francesca, the tombs of Luxor, and Turkish marketplaces. Also found with the diaries are a few sketches, a list of expenses, and a chronology for March and April of 1924.
  There is also a diary Faulkner kept during the summer of 1956 documenting general social, artistic, and daily events. Topics include Gifford Beal, Maxfield Parrish, Paul Manship, Eric Gugler, Saint-Gaudens Memorial trustee meetings, and gardening. Also found in this diary is a short biographical sketch of Faulkner and a list of works gifted to friends.
  - New Hampshire Diary, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - Five Travel Diaries, 1922-1924, (5 folders) (Box 2, Folder 59-63)
- Printed Materials, circa 1858-1966, Series 6:; (Box 2-3; 8 folders)
  Clippings are of published writings by Faulkner, obituaries and published remembrances of Faulkner, local events in Keene, New Hampshire, and reproductions of Faulkner's artwork. Also found here are exhibition catalogs for various other artists, a reproduction of an engraving of spectactors looking at Hiram Powers' sculpture "The Greek Slave," and an announcement of Faulkner's death by the American Academy of Arts and Letters. Other publications include Lawrence Grant White's translation of the first canto of Dante's Inferno, and The Charters of Freedom, reproductions of the Bill of rights and the Declaration of Independence illustrated by Faulkner's murals for the National Archives. Also found is a copy of the Keene newspaper from 1879.
  A portion of this series has been scanned. Materials not scanned are exhibition catalogs of other artists, the printed reproduction of the Greek Slave, and the translation of Dante's Inferno.
  - Announcement from the American Academy of Arts and Letters, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - Clippings, 1925-1960s, (2 folders; oversized in Box 3) (Box 2, Folder 65-66)
  - Dante's Inferno, 1925, (not scanned) (Box 2, Folder 67)
  - Exhibition Catalogs: Others, 1946-1966, (not scanned) (Box 2, Folder 68)
    (Jane Canfield, Frances Grimes, Alexander James, and Paul Manship)
  - Printed reproduction of the Greek Slave, circa 1858, (not scanned) (Box 2, Folder 69)
  - Charters of Freedom, undated, (not scanned) (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Oversized Clippings, 1879, (Scanned with Box 2, Folders 63-64) (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Photographs, 1892-1960s, Series 7:; (Box 2-3; 15 folders)
  Photographs include portraits and photographs of Faulkner, of Faulkner with his dog Slipper, and a photograph of Faulkner with Paul Manship. Also found are portraits of James Earle Fraser and Paul Manship, a photograph of Augustus Saint-Gaudens' studio, a landscape in Dublin, New Hampshire, and a photograph of Faulkner's studio.
  There are many photographs of Faulkner's artwork, including drawings, paintings, and murals for the Eastman School of Music, the National Archives, the Oregon State Capitol, and the New Hampshire Capitol Building. Photographs of artwork by others includes pieces by Gifford Beal, George Bellows, Paul Manship, Augustus Saint-Gaudens, and Abbott Handerson Thayer.
  Also found is one photograph album from Faulkner's adolescence and twenties, and another album of photographs primarily from the mid to late 1930s. The first album contains photographs of Faulkner, pictures of Keene, New Hampshire, landscapes, leisure activities, family photographs, and informal pictures of unidentified people. Of special interest are photographs of Faulkner fencing and camping with a person who appears to be Witter Bynner. The bulk of the photographs in the second album are of Faulkner's New Hampshire home "The Bounty." Also found are pictures of social events, the landscape around the house, Faulkner at work and with his dog Slipper, and locations in New England.
  The bulk of this series has been scanned, except for photographs of works of art.
  - Barry Faulkner, 1892-1962 (Box 2, Folder 70)
  - Barry Faulkner With Others, 1905-1936 (Box 2, Folder 71)
  - Artwork, 1937-1945, (3 folders; not scanned) (Box 2, Folder 72-74)
  - Artwork, circa 1900s-1930s, (not scanned) (Box 2, Folder 75)
  - Artwork By Others, 1901-circa 1940s, (not scanned) (Box 2, Folder 76)
  - Artists, 1901-circa 1920s (Box 2, Folder 77)
  - Family and Friends, circa 1900s-1960s (Box 2, Folder 78)
  - New Hampshire, 1911 (Box 2, Folder 79)
  - Dismantled Photo Albums, circa 1880s-1900s, (Oversized housed in Box 3) (Box 2, Folder 80)
  - Studio, circa 1930s (Box 2, Folder 81)
  - Dismantled Photo Album, 1923-1948, (4 folders; scanned with Box 2, Folder 77) (Box 3 (sol), Folder 5-8)
- Scrapbook, 1951, Series 8:; (Box 3; 2 folders)
  Found here is a scrapbook of Faulkner's 70th birthday in 1951 that includes photographs of Faulkner with friends, photographs from his birthday party, telegrams with birthday greetings, birthday cards, and letters. Of special interest is a drawing and poem by Nick and Frederika James, a song by the Platts, a poem by Lawrence Grant White, and placecards with hand drawn illustrations depicting the "taste and characteristics" of Faulkner.
  - Scrapbook For 70th Birthday, 1951, (2 folders) (Box 3, Folder 9-10)